

Lara Ramos Poblet

WEB DEVELOPER

Web developer with experience as a Frontend Developer and a background in social work with a focus on disability. Committed to merging technology and social awareness to create web solutions with a positive impact on people's lives.

- linkedin.com/in/lararamospoblet
- Lrpoblet@gmail.com
- Madrid, Spain

Click here to view my portfolio

EXPERIENCE



FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Kairós Digital Solutions S.L.

March 2023 - August 2023

- · Development of web components in Native JavaScript (Vanilla JS) using
- Improvement of accessibility (WCAG 2.1) and performance of Kairós' commercial website.
- Testing with Jest and Cypress.
- docker-compose.
- Project development using React and Styled-components.
- · Version control with Git.
- · API calls.

SOCIAL WORKER



January 2019 - September 2022



SOCIAL WORKER

Asociación AMI-3

December 2016 - December 2018

- LitElement.
- Use of CI/CD pipelines, Docker and





RECENT COURSES (view more in portfolio)



ACCESIBLE CODE

The A11Y Collective

August 2023 - Currently





Lemoncode

May 2023





Platzi

February 2023

SKILLS























Spanish Sign Language: B2

EDUCATION

KAIROSDS

WEB DEVELOPMENT

Generación K | March 2023 - April 2023

Git, DevOps (Docker), Web Accessibility, JavaScript (ES6+), Jest, LitElement, Cypress and Firebase.



Adalab | September 2022 - December 2022

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, mobile first and responsive design.

JavaScript (ES6) and third-party web services (APIs).

Version control with Git.

Creating SPAs with React Node.js, ExpressJS, and SQL/SQLite.

Proficient in Slack, Github, VS Code, Gulp, Terminal, Linter, Zeplin...



MASTER'S IN SUPPORT FOR PEOPLE WITH **DISABILITIES AND/OR DEVELOPMENTAL DISORDERS**

UAM-Plena Inclusión | 2015 - 2017



WEB DEVELOPMENT

Escuela de Organización Industrial 2016

Advanced HTML, CSS, and responsive design. HTML JavaScript APIs.

DOM and jQuery Single-page app using Angular



GRADO EN TRABAJO SOCIAL UCM 2009 - 2013

Lara Ramos Poblet

WEB DEVELOPER

- <u>linkedin.com/in/lararamospoblet</u>
- <u>Lrpoblet@gmail.com</u>
- Madrid, Spain

ABOUT ME

I studied Social Work and specialized in the area of disability. My interest in technology and curiosity led me to an exciting transition to the world of Web Development.

Recently, I have had the opportunity to work as a Frontend Developer at Kairós Digital Solutions, where I have created reusable JavaScript components with LitElement and improved the accessibility and performance of their commercial website. I have also applied tests with Jest and Cypress and worked on continuous integration and deployments with Docker, among other fundamental tasks. In addition to my experience with the aforementioned technologies, I have also worked on several projects using React as my main framework and SASS for styles. In the past, I have also done projects with AngularJS, so I would have no problem picking it up and updating myself on its latest versions.

My adaptability, attention to detail, curiosity, and proactivity are qualities that I have developed and perfected throughout my career. Additionally, my background in social work has given me a unique and empathetic perspective on the importance of technology in society, enhancing my understanding of community needs and problem-solving.

My commitment to the constant evolution of the IT sector is reflected in my enthusiasm for learning and adapting to new technologies. My current goal is to merge my technical skills with my empathy and social perspective to create inclusive and accessible digital solutions. I firmly believe that technology can make a difference in people's lives and I am excited to be part of that change.

Click here to view my portfolio

Estimado/a receptor/a de esta carta:

Me complace escribir esta carta de recomendación para Lara Ramos Poblet, quien ha trabajado conmigo como desarrollador/a frontend durante 6 meses.

Como desarrolladora frontend, Lara tiene habilidades técnicas sólidas para la experiencia que tiene y demuestra un gran conocimiento en HTML, CSS y JavaScript.

Es capaz de diseñar y desarrollar sitios web y aplicaciones de calidad y fácilmente navegables, y es capaz de resolver problemas técnicos de manera efectiva y eficiente.

También tiene conocimiento para utilizar frameworks como React y Angular, librerías como Lit para componentes web nativos y herramientas como Git y Docker.

Sin embargo, lo que realmente destaca de Lara es su actitud y motivación. Siempre está dispuesta a aprender y mejorar sus habilidades, y muestra una gran capacidad de trabajo en equipo.

Se comunica bien con sus compañeros de trabajo y está siempre dispuesta a colaborar en proyectos en equipo. Además, siempre está buscando maneras de mejorar el rendimiento del equipo y los procesos.

Su actitud es contagiosa y ha tenido un impacto positivo en nuestro equipo, y estoy seguro/a de que hará lo mismo en cualquier otra empresa en la que trabaje. Sin duda recomendaría a Lara para cualquier puesto relacionado con el desarrollo frontend.

Por favor, no dude en ponerse en contacto conmigo si necesita más información.

Atentamente,

Mánu Fosela

Head of Software Development & Devops

+34 639 01 89 87

manu.fosela@kairosds.com

Kairós Digital Solutions Caleruega 102, 28033 Madrid